Guide to the Chancellor of the University of Pittsburgh, Wesley W. Posvar, Administrative Files, 1967-1991 UA.2.10.1967-1991
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Academic Year 1990/91, XXIV.
  - Associations and Organizations, 1990-1991; 1000.0.
    - University Aviation Association (UAA) (Box 65, Folder 1046.0.)
    - Children's Hospital (Box 65, Folder 1048.0.)
    - German American National Congress (DANK) (Box 65, Folder 1049.0.)
  - Colleges and Universities, 1990-1991; 1100.0.
    - Colleges and Universities - General (Box 66, Folder 1100.0.)
    - Publications (Box 66, Folder 1100.1-1100.1b)
    - Published Remarks (Box 66, Folder 1100.01a)
    - Position Announcements (Box 66, Folder 1100.2.)
    - Positions Announcements (Box 67, Folder 1100.2a)
    - Penn State University (Box 67, Folder 1101.0.)
    - University of Pennsylvania (Box 67, Folder 1103.0.)
    - Carnegie Mellon University (Box 67, Folder 1104.0.)
    - Community College of Allegheny County, Chatham College and Point Park College (Box 67, Folder 1107.0.)
- Additions to Academic Year Files, XXV.
  These files were delivered to the University Archives as part of the records of Chancellor Dennis O'Connor, but originate and pertain to the term of Chancellor Posvar. They have been arranged chronologically and then by mail log number, as were the files in the previous record groups.
  - Harvard-Yale-Princeton Club of Pittsburgh, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 3.6)
  - ROTC, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 7.5)
  - NAACP, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 8.6)
  - Middle East Trip, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 1.16.1)
  - Pennsylvania State University and Temple, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 8.13)
  - Board of Trustees Investment Committee, Information Meeting, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 3.1.9)
  - University Senate Budget Policies, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 302.0.)
  - Jewish Community Center, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 502.0b)
  - Neuroscience Program, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 700.0.)
  - University Planning, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 600.0b)
  - Executive Staff Meeting, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 200.8.1)
  - Brakeley Compensation Report, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 600.0.)
  - Advisory Council on Regional Development, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 803.3)
  - Association of American Universities, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 913.0.)
  - Business-higher Education Forum, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 1005.1)
  - School of Education - Board of Visitors, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 801.2a)
  - Allegheny Conference on Community Development, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 1001.0-1001.0a)
  - American Assembly, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 1002.0.)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 1003.0.)
  - American Association of University Professors, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 1004.0.)
  - International Council on Education for Teaching, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 1040.0.)
  - Administrative Actions Approved by the Board of Trustees, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 104.0.)
  - Trustee Assignments, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 105.0.)
  - Commonwealth Trustees, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 106.0.)
  - Board of Trustees Committees, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 107.0.)
  - Budget-Audit Committee, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 107.1)
  - Student Affairs Committee, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 107.2)
  - Office of the President - General, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 201.0.)
  - President and Mrs. Posvar's Christmas Cassette, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 201.0.)
  - West Point, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 201.3)
  - Pittsburgh Public Schools, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 403.1)
  - Distinguished Service Professor Nomination, Roger Ahlbrandt, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 800.0.)
  - International Council on Education for Teaching, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1040.0.)
  - Provost Weingartner, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 800.0-800.0b)
  - George Love Oral History Project, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 801.13)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences (FAS), African Studies, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 802.0.)
  - FAS - Board of Visitors, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 802.1)
  - FAS Gazette, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 802.2)
  - Superconducting Super Collider, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 802.3)
  - Theatre Arts, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 802.4)
  - Mellon Professors, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 802.6)
  - College of Arts and Sciences, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 802.12)
  - International Council on Education for Teaching, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 1040.0.)
  - Recruiting Requests, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 200.3)
  - FAS Dean for Graduate Studies Search, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 200.6)
  - Vice President for Student Affairs Search, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 200.6a)
  - Vice President for Finance Search, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 200.6b)
  - School of Health Related Professions Dean Search, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 200.6c)
  - School of Dental Medicine Dean Search, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 200.6d)
  - Graduate School of Public Health Dean Search, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 200.6e)
  - Strategic Planning Guidelines for the 1990s, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 201.28)
  - University Relations and Development, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 600.0.)
  - Johnstown Planning and Budget Conference, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 800.19)
  - Self-Study Questionnaire for Review of Engineering Programs, Mechanical Engineering, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 801.3c)
  - Chautauqua Institute, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 801.7h)
  - Association of American Universities, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 1008.0.)
  - Board of Trustees Meeting Agendas, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 100.0.)
  - Board of Trustees Annual Meeting, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 103.0.)
  - Board of Trustees Investment Committee, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 107.5)
  - United States Space Foundation, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 201.9)
  - United States Space Foundation Executive Board, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 201.9a)
  - United States Space Foundation Publications, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 201.9b)
  - President's Committee on the Arts and the Humanities, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 201.12b)
  - Environmental Management and Sustainable Development, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 201.12b)
  - Environmental Management and Sustainable Development, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 201.12b)
  - Salary Resolutions by Senate Budget Policies Committee, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 201.28)
  - National Advisory Council for Environmental Policy and Technology, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 204.4)
  - University Relations and Development, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 600.0.)
  - Forbes Reinsurance Co., 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 702.1-702.1a)
  - Meetings with Provost Henderson, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 800.2)
  - Professors Emeritus, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 800.4)
  - Provost's Deans and Regional Campus Presidents Meetings, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 800.5)
  - President Posvar's School Visits, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 806.0.)
  - Distinguished Service Professors, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 800.7)
  - Provost's Advisory Committee on Women's Concerns, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 800.9)
  - Scientific and Engineering Computing, Supercomputer, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 800.11)
  - Affirmative Action Committee, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 800.13)
  - Katz Graduate School of Business, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 801.1)
  - University of Pittsburgh Medical Center, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 908.0-908.0a)
  - Presbyterian Hospital Executive Committee, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 908.1)
  - Presbyterian University Hospital, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 908.1a)
  - Eye and Ear Hospital, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 908.3)
  - Montefiore Hospital, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 908.5)
  - Association of American Universities, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 1008.0.)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 1010.0-1010.0d)
- Subject Files, XXVI.
  This record group includes information regarding the Chancellor's Residence on Devonshire Street, including photographs of the home's interior and items owned by the Posvar family and the University. Other files include records concerning faculty unionization and the University's efforts to enroll a more diverse student body. The development of the Medical and Health Care Division of the University of Pittsburgh and long-range planning process are also represented. In addition, there are files containing some of Chancellor Posvar's speeches from 1972 to 1978, records pertaining to some of Posvar's non-University activities, and information regarding his retirement from the University in 1991.
  - Inventory and Appraisal of Items at the Chancellor's Residence (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Photographs of University Art in the Chancellor's Residence (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Photographs of University Silver in the Chancellor's Residence (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Photographs of University Items in the Chancellor's Residence (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Photographs of Posvar Art in the Chancellor's Residence (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Photographs of Posvar Silver in the Chancellor's Residence (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Photographs of Posvar Family Photos in the Chancellor's Residence (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Photographs of Posvar Items in the Chancellor's Residence (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Photographs of Items Belonging to the University and Posvar in the Chancellor's Residence (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Photographs of Carpets and Oriental Rugs in the Chancellor's Residence (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Photographs of Unidentified Art in the Chancellor's Residence (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Photographs of Unidentified Items in the Chancellor's Residence (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Photographs of Chancellor's Residence Basement and Garage (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Chancellor's Residence (Box 4, Folder 2-3)
  - Office of the Vice Chancellor for Health Professions (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - School of Medicine Clinical Practice Plan, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 5-7)
  - Medical and Health Care Division (MHCD) and Health Sciences Annual Report, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Faculty Union, 1972-1976 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Report of the Ad Hoc Committee on Unionization and Collective Bargaining of the American Philosophical Association, May 1976 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Faculty Union, 1983-1986 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Faculty Union, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Minority Recruitment and Commonwealth Equal Opportunity Program for Higher Education, 1983-1985 (Box 4, Folder 15-19)
  - University Plan Revision, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - University Planning Policies for the 1980s (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - University Long-Range Planning Policies, March 1984 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Report of the Faculty Task Force on Planning (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Academic Priorities, Draft, November 19, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Academic Priorities, Fiscal Year 1984 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - School of Education Planning, November 1984 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Academic Priorities and Planning, November 1984 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Provost's Planning Process Final Recommendations: Discussion of Proposed Changes, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - University Plan, Final Recommendations, March 15, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - President's Statement to Trustees on the University Plan, Draft, May 21, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - University Plan: Report to the Board of Trustees, Draft, May 25, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - University Plan: Report to the Board of Trustees, June 3, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - University Plan, Draft, June 6, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - University Plan, Jack Freeman Revisions, June 9, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - University Plan, Draft, June 10, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - University Plan, Roger Ahlbrandt Revisions, June 12, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - University Plan, Draft, June 13, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - University Plan, Posvar Draft, June 13, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - University Plan, Board of Trustees Submitted Draft, June 13, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - University Plan, Draft, June 14, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - University Plan, Revisions, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Volume Two, Report of the President, May 20, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Statement on State Appropriations, February 7, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Report of Artwork, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Audited Financial Statements, Forbes Reinsurance Company Limited, July 31, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Pennsylvania Department of Education Budget Presentation, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Executive Staff Compensation Criteria, April 16, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Athletics, 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - The Functioning of the College and University Presidency, Stanford University, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Posvar Non-University Committees (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Foreign Policy and Defense Task Force, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - China Trip, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Federal Emergency Management Agency, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Alexander M. Haig for President Campaign, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Posvar Daily Planners, 1987-1991 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Staff Classification and Pay Plan, January 1, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Posvar Resignation, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Posvar Statements to the University, September 1991 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Personal Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Harvard University Commencement, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Notes on Science and Technology Training (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Posvar Speeches, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Posvar Speeches, January-March 1972 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Posvar Speeches, April-June 1972 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Posvar Speeches, July-December 1972 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Posvar Speeches, March-May 1973 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Posvar Speeches, June-December 1973 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Posvar Speeches, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Posvar Speeches, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Posvar Speeches, January-February 1976 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Posvar Speeches, March-October 1976 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Posvar Speeches, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Posvar Speeches, February-March 1978 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Posvar Speeches, April-December 1978 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Dean Jerome Zoffer Surprise Luncheon Speech, May 22, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Security (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Agreement with Comenius University in Bratislava, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Advisory Council on Regional Development (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - John Woodruff, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Senior Vice President for Administration, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - K. Leroy Irvis (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Mark Nordenberg (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - "Looking Back... Looking Ahead," Economic Development Partnership, November 1990 (Box 18, Cassette 1)
- Executive and Senior Staff Meetings, 1988-1989; XXVII.
  - Senior Staff Meeting, November 1988 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Senior Staff Meetings, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Executive Staff Meetings, September 1988 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Executive Staff Meetings, October 1988 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Executive Staff Meetings, November 1988 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Executive Staff Meetings, December 1988 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Executive Staff Meetings, January 1989 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Executive Staff Meetings, February 1989 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Executive Staff Meetings, March 1989 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Executive Staff Meetings, April 1989 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Executive Staff Meetings, May 1989 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Executive Staff Meetings, June 1989 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Executive Staff Meetings, July 1989 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Executive Staff Meetings, August 1989 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Executive Staff Meetings, September 1989 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Executive Staff Meetings, October 1989 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Executive Staff Meetings, November 1989 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Executive Staff Meetings, December 1989 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Chronological Files, XXVIII.
  - Chronological Files, January 1971-March 1975 (Box 7, Folder 11-25)
  - Chronological Files, April 1975-December 1978 (Box 8, Folder 1-10)
  - Chronological Files, July 1983-April 1984 (Box 8, Folder 11-20)
  - Chronological Files, May 1984-June 1985 (Box 9, Folder 1-14)
  - Chronological Files, July 1985-May 1986 (Box 10, Folder 1-14)
  - Chronological Files, June 1986-June 1987 (Box 11, Folder 1-14)
  - Chronological Files, July 1987-May 1988 (Box 12, Folder 1-14)
  - Chronological Files, June 1988-January 1989 (Box 13, Folder 1-15)
  - Chronological Files, February-November 1989 (Box 14, Folder 1-17)
  - Chronological Files, November 1989-August 1990 (Box 15, Folder 1-15)
  - Chronological Files, September 1990-July 1991 (Box 16, Folder 1-17)